<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<data>
    <learn-concept-view>
        <section id="58" handle="concepts">Concepts</section>
        <entry id="33147" tutorials="0" tutorial-steps="1" articles="0" concepts="3" tasks="0" resources="1" issues="0">
            <audiences>
                <item handle="beginners">Beginners</item>
                <item handle="users">Users</item>
                <item handle="developers">Developers</item>
            </audiences>
            <description mode="formatted"><h4>Overview</h4>
<p>Entries are individual records in a <a rel="concept" href="sections">section</a>, and comprise the bulk of a Symphony project’s data. In a &#8220;Blog Posts&#8221; section, for example, each individual post would be an entry. Once saved, entries can be retrieved by <a rel="concept">data sources</a> and made available to <a rel="concept">pages</a> for display on the front end.</p>
<h4>Usage</h4>
<p>A section&#8217;s entries can be created and managed in the <a rel="concept">admin interface</a>. The exact location will depend on the name of the section to which they belong (and that section&#8217;s <a rel="concept" href="navigation groups">navigation group</a>), but the formula is simple: in the main menu, <code>{Navigation Group} &gt; {Section}</code>.</p>
<p>The default view is a table of entries, or an <em>index view</em>. The index view provides a paginated list of the entries in a section, and allows for some bulk editing operations. To select entries in the index view, simply click their table rows. Once entries have been selected, bulk actions are available via the &#8220;With Selected&#8221; dropdown at the bottom right of the table. Available actions include deleting entries and setting the value of checkbox or select box fields.</p>
<h4>Details</h4>
<p>The structure of entries is determined by a section’s fields, but all entries are given a unique numerical <a rel="concept" href="system-ids">system ID</a> and a <a rel="concept" href="system-dates">system date</a> (date of creation). Though hidden, these fields are made available to data sources for sorting, <a rel="concept" href="data-source-filters">filtering</a>, and/or output.</p></description>
            <name handle="entries">Entries</name>
            <summary mode="formatted"><p>Entries represent individual content records in a section.</p></summary>
        </entry>
    </learn-concept-view>
</data>