<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<data>
    <learn-tutorial-view>
        <section id="59" handle="tutorials">Tutorials</section>
        <entry id="33078" tutorial-steps="5">
            <audiences>
                <item handle="beginners">Beginners</item>
                <item handle="developers">Developers</item>
                <item handle="users">Users</item>
            </audiences>
            <conclusion mode="formatted"><p>Congratulations, you've just installed Symphony! Before you jump out of your chair for a celebratory dance, we've got a little cleaning up to do:</p>
<ol><li>First, delete the (<code>/install</code>) folder. If you used an FTP client to upload your files, just select the file and delete it. If you used the command line, `cd` to the root of your Symphony installation and do: <code>rm install.php</code>.</li>
<li>Second, be sure to tighten up the folder permissions you adjusted in Step 3. Exact settings will depend on your server environment, but the permissions on your root directory and your <code>symphony/</code> directory should be fairly restrictive (try something like 755). Then set <code>manifest/</code> and <code>workspace/</code> to 775 (make the <code>workspace/</code> permissions recursive, so they apply to its subdirectories as well).
<pre><code>chmod 755 symphony .
chmod -R 775 manifest
chmod -R 775 workspace</code></pre></li>
</ol><p><em>Now</em> you can dance (try not to embarrass yourself too badly). When you're finished, log into your Symphony <a>admin interface</a> (<code>http://yourdomain.com/symphony</code>) and look around. The real fun is about to begin...</p>
<h5>What to do Next</h5>
<ul><li>Check out the <a href="/learn/beginners">Beginner's Guide</a>, which will point you directly to the resources that are most helpful for those just getting to know the system.</li>
<li><a href="/get-involved/member/new/">Join the community</a> so you can ask questions and get help from other Symphonists.</li>
<li>Beef up your installation with Symphony <a href="/downloads/extensions">extensions</a></li>
</ul></conclusion>
            <date-modified time="09:35" weekday="3">2009-10-21</date-modified>
            <date-published time="09:35" weekday="3">2009-10-21</date-published>
            <introduction mode="formatted"><p>Installing Symphony is a fairly simple and straightforward process. This tutorial will walk you through the options available during installation and show you how to get the system up and running in no time.</p>
<p>The first thing we'll do is make sure your server's got everything it needs to run Symphony smoothly. Then we'll talk about the two available installation methods—package-based and Git-based—and outline the benefits of each. Once you've chosen a method, we'll show you how to get Symphony onto your server, and we'll finish preparing for the installation by creating a database. Finally we'll run the install script, do a little cleanup, and point you toward a few additional resources.</p>
<p>Ready?</p></introduction>
            <summary mode="formatted"><p>A quick, easy guide to help you get Symphony up and running in just a few minutes.</p></summary>
            <title handle="install-symphony">Install Symphony</title>
        </entry>
    </learn-tutorial-view>
    <learn-tutorial-resources>
        <section id="64" handle="resources">Resources</section>
        <error>No records found.</error>
    </learn-tutorial-resources>
    <learn-tutorial-step>
        <section id="60" handle="tutorial-steps">Tutorial Steps</section>
        <entry id="33218">
            <description mode="formatted"><p>Creating a database for Symphony to use is a fairly simple step, but to proceed, you'll need to know your MySQL username and password. These may have been assigned by your hosting provider, or you may have created them using your server's control panel. </p>
<p>Depending on your host, you may have several different options for creating a MySQL database, including phpMyAdmin, the command line MySQL client, and other host-specific options. If you're unsure which options are available to you, or you aren't able to use one of the methods below, consult your hosting provider's documentation.</p>
<h5>Using phpMyAdmin</h5>
<ol>
<li>Log into your phpMyAdmin interface.</li>
<li>You'll see a field on the home page labeled "Create new database." Enter a database name (note this for the next step), and from the "Collation" dropdown, select <code>utf8_unicode_ci</code>.</li>
<li>Click the "Create" button.</li>
</ol>
<h5>Using the Command Line MySQL Client</h5>
<ol>
<li>SSH into your server</li>
<li>Connect to the MySQL client:
<pre><code>mysql -u username -p</code></pre>
Replace <code>username</code> with your MySQL username. You'll be prompted for your MySQL password. Enter it.
</li>
<li>In the MySQL prompt (<code>mysql></code>), type:
<pre><code>CREATE DATABASE db_name CHARACTER SET utf8 COLLATE utf8_unicode_ci;</code></pre>
(Be sure to replace <code>db_name</code> with a suitable database name, like <code>symphony</code>).You should see a message telling you that the query was executed. Type <code>EXIT</code>.</li>
</ol></description>
            <name handle="create-a-database">Create a Database</name>
            <step-number>4</step-number>
        </entry>
    </learn-tutorial-step>
    <learn-tutorial-step-resources>
        <section id="64" handle="resources">Resources</section>
        <error>No records found.</error>
    </learn-tutorial-step-resources>
    <learn-tutorial-steps>
        <section id="60" handle="tutorial-steps">Tutorial Steps</section>
        <entry id="33100">
            <name handle="check-server-requirements">Check Server Requirements</name>
            <step-number>1</step-number>
        </entry>
        <entry id="33215">
            <name handle="review-installation-options">Review Installation Options</name>
            <step-number>2</step-number>
        </entry>
        <entry id="33216">
            <name handle="get-symphony-onto-your-server">Get Symphony onto Your Server</name>
            <step-number>3</step-number>
        </entry>
        <entry id="33218">
            <name handle="create-a-database">Create a Database</name>
            <step-number>4</step-number>
        </entry>
        <entry id="33217">
            <name handle="run-the-install-script">Run the Install Script</name>
            <step-number>5</step-number>
        </entry>
    </learn-tutorial-steps>
</data>