<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<data>
    <learn-concept-view>
        <section id="58" handle="concepts">Concepts</section>
        <entry id="33214" tutorials="0" tutorial-steps="0" articles="0" concepts="0" tasks="0" resources="0" issues="0">
            <audiences>
                <item handle="beginners">Beginners</item>
                <item handle="users">Users</item>
                <item handle="developers">Developers</item>
            </audiences>
            <description mode="formatted"><h4>Overview</h4>
<p>Handles are strings that are generated for all Symphony pages, and by certain <a rel="concept">field types</a> to provide sanitized, URL-friendly equivalents for the values they store. For example, a text input with the value “Symphony, it’s for Ninjas” would have the following handle autogenerated for it: <code>symphony-its-for-ninjas</code>. Handles are often used for filtering data sources and populating data source output parameters.</p>
<p>Of the core field types, <a rel="concept" href="field-types#text-input">Text Input</a>, <a rel="concept" href="field-types#tag-list">Tag List</a>, <a rel="concept" href="field-types#select-box">Select Box</a>, and <a rel="concept" href="field-types#select-box-link">Select Box Link</a> provide handles for their values.</p>
<h4>Usage</h4>
<p>Handles are autogenerated for pages and for supported fields whenever the value of the field changes.</p>
<p>When using a handle-enabled field to <a rel="concept" href="data-source-filters">filter a data source</a> or populate a <a rel="concept" href="data-source-output-parameters">data source output parameter</a>, the handle will be used in place of the actual value. Fields that create relationships between sections, like Select Box Link, are an exception to this rule. The <a rel="concept" href="system-ids">system ID</a> of the related entry will be used instead.</p></description>
            <name handle="handles">Handles</name>
            <parents>
                <item id="33147" handle="entries" section-handle="concepts" section-name="Concepts">Entries</item>
            </parents>
            <summary mode="formatted"><p>Handles provide sanitized, URL-friendly equivalents for the values stored by many field types.</p></summary>
        </entry>
    </learn-concept-view>
</data>